# **Erick Latshaw**

South Yarmouth, MA | (774)-212-5937 | erickjlatshaw@gmail.com | Linkedin | Github | Portfolio

Junior Game Programmer/Software Engineer

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a passionate programmer and game developer with abilities in both 2D and 3D game creation. I have experience working in game jams as well as larger team projects. I am incredibly comfortable with version control and I pride myself in my clean code and game architecture with an emphasis on making designer-friendly, decoupled systems.

- Developed dozens of game systems to make the implementation of new mechanics seamless.
- Designed and developed at least six titles, with two in the process of being shipped late 2022 where I served as lead engineer.
- 4 years studying game development, and 7 years studying software development

#### **SKILLS**

Git, Unity, Unreal Engine, Godot, C#, C++, GDScript, Java, Python, MySQL, OOP, Agile, Scrum

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

JUNE 2022 - JULY 2022

Marist College, Poughkeepsie, NY | TA for Game Design and Programming 1

- Taught a group of 20 highschool students Godot over an intensive 3-week period.
- Created Syllabus and lesson plans.
- Taught game design patterns, clean code principles, and data structures.

SEPTEMBER 2018 - MARCH 2020

## Marist College, Poughkeepsie, NY | Student Data Analyst

- Worked to enhance and train a model to predict students' final grades so they could be contacted for additional support.
- Gained real-world experience in data science.
- Group project experience both virtual and in-person.
- Regular use of MySQL, Python, and Git.
- Helped migrate databases from Netezza to MariaDB server.

# **PROJECT EXPERIENCE**

FEBRUARY 2022 - PRESENT

Whispering Abyss, Unity, 21-person Team - 3D Roquelike with Lovecraftian Themes

- Lead Engineer, oversaw, designed, and engineered a number of systems in the game.
- Managed the codebase with Github, enforced a style guide and project organization.
- Followed Agile methodology and scrums.

## **EDUCATION**

August 2018 - May 2022

Marist College, Poughkeepsie, NY

BS, Games & Emerging Media - Technical Concentration